When 400,000 men couldn't get home, home came for them.
Dunkirk is a war, action, drama film directed by Christopher Nolan.
The story of the miraculous evacuation of Allied soldiers from Belgium, Britain, Canada and France, who were cut off and surrounded
by the German army from the beaches and harbour of Dunkirk between May 26th and June 4th 1940 during World War II.
Tommy, played by Fionn Whitehead.
Farrier, played by Tom Hardy.
Mr. Dawson, played by Mark Rylance.
Commander Bolton, played by Kenneth Branagh.
Shivering Soldier, played by Cillian Murphy.
George, played by Barry Keoghan.
Dunkirk is a 2017 historical war film produced, written, and directed by Christopher Nolan that depicts the
Dunkirk evacuation of World War II from the perspectives of people on the land, sea, and air.
It features an ensemble cast including Fionn Whitehead, Tom Glynn-Carney, Jack Lowden, Harry Styles in his feature film debut,
Aneurin Barnard, James D'Arcy, Barry Keoghan, Kenneth Branagh, Cillian Murphy, Mark Rylance, and Tom Hardy.
The film portrays the evacuation with little dialogue, as Nolan sought
instead to create suspense through cinematography and music.
Filming began in May 2016 in Dunkirk and wrapped that
September in Los Angeles, when post-production began.
Cinematographer Hoyte van Hoytema shot the film on IMAX
65 mm and 65 mm large-format film stock.
Dunkirk has extensive practical effects.
It employed thousands of extras as well as historic boats
from the evacuation, and period aeroplanes.
Distributed by Warner Bros.
Pictures, Dunkirk premiered at Odeon Leicester Square in London, a few days before
its release in the United Kingdom and United States on 21 July 2017.
It grossed over $530 million worldwide, making it the highest-grossing World War
II film until it was surpassed by Nolan's Oppenheimer (2023).
Dunkirk received praise for its screenplay, direction, editing, score, sound design and cinematography; some critics called
it Nolan's best work, and one of the greatest war films as well as one of the greatest movies of the 2010s.
It received various accolades, including eight nominations at the 90th
Academy Awards, including Best Picture and Best Director.
It went on to win for Best Sound Editing, Best
Sound Mixing, and Best Film Editing.
The film explores themes of army, beach, france, allies, military officer.
The tone is emotional and intense.